Carlos Moreno

Curriculum Vitae

Cll. 57 1B - 74 $\bigcirc +57\ 318\ 606\ 8507$ ⊠ carmoreno.jpg@gmail.com

"What we know is a drop, what we don't know is an ocean." – Isaac Newton

Personal Information

Name Carlos Andrés Moreno Vélez

Nationality Colombiano

LinkedIn https://co.linkedin.com/in/carmoreno1

Qwiklabs https://bit.ly/395guA9

Blog https://carmoreno.com.co

Profile

Python Developer

Carlos is a Computer Engineer from Universidad del Valle, he has 4+ years of experience in Software Development with Python Technologies mainly. He has built Apis REST using technologies like Django Rest Framework and CherryPy and desktop solutions with PvQt/PvQt5 together to MvSQL, PostgreSQL and Git. He studied around one year in EF English Live academy, where He achieved a C1 (upper-intermediate) English level and He continues improving this topic currently.

He has been exploring Data Science technologies gaining knowledge in Pandas and Numpy studing a Diploma Course at Universidad Nacional de Colombia during 4 months. As like as Cloud technologies using GCP, studing in Qwiklabs. Others technologies which he has knowledge include Lumen, ReactJs, AngularJs Html5 and Css3.

Resourceful, disciplined, restless and always willing to contribute and learn from the work group

Experience

Professional

Dic. 2020 - Current Python Developer Ssr. Adavanced, Globant, Cali, Colombia, Data and AI Studio.

- Collaborate on a multi-disciplinary team of developers, testers, data architects, devops in order to create and maintain new reports and data for Education information analysis.
- Manage Gigabytes of sensible data about Students, Teachers, US Districts and Schools.
- Led 2 initiatives: Data Quality and Database Migrations to improve the development experience in the team.
- o Coordinate meetings with team members from India and LATAM.
- Language and tools used: Python, Shell, Git, Pandas, Flyway, Airflow, Jupyter Notebook, PostgreSQL, Jira, AWS (Redshift, S3, Datapipeline).

Feb. 2020 - Nov. 2020 Python Developer, Servinformación, Cali, Colombia, Backend Team.

- "Data Rutas Project": Developed new REST endpoints using a framework legacy version (Django Rest Framework v1.4).
- "Servihuella Project": Integrated data from different sources in collaboration with the Secretary of Health and Mayor of Santiago de Cali. Worked with a total of 5 members on the team among Developers, Stakeholders and Managers.
- "Servihuella Project": Automated the cleaning and storing process of daily data related to COVID-19 using Big data technologies.
- Initiated the automated report generations building a desktop application that took 10 Excel files and generated 2 final Excel reports.
- Language and tools used: Python 2.7 and 3+, Django Rest Framework v1.4 (legacy version), CherryPy, Pandas, PyQt, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Git, GCP (Big Query, Cloud SQL, Lambda Functions, App Engine, Cloud Scheduler).

Dec. 2018 - Oct. 2019 Software Engineer, El País Newspaper, Cali, Colombia, Technology Department.

- o "Digital Subscriptions Project": Developed new REST Endpoints to integrate with Subscriptions providers like Piano (https://piano.io/)
- "Digital Subscriptions Project": Produced a new web application to use as a back-office, in order to sell Digital Subscriptions.
- "Digital Subscriptions Project": Communicated with differents providers members of Piano to resolve doubts about their product, via email or online conferences
- Language and tools used: Javascript, AngularJS, Git, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, PHP, Lumen.

Dec. 2017 - Nov. 2018 **Django / Angular Developer**, *Markaf Colombia*, Tuluá, Colombia, *Development Team*.

- "Markaf App Project": Modeled the internal pay schema of the application: Tables, relations among tables and triggers.
- $\circ\,\,$ "Markaf App Project": Developed new REST endpoint according to stakeholders requests.
- "Markaf App Project": Participated in some frontend tasks, developed Angular visual components according to UI/UX team needs.
- Language and tools used: Python, Django Rest Framework, Javascript, Angular5, Git, PostgreSQL.

Education

Jan. 2021 - Jan. 2022 EF C1 English Level - Adavanced, EF English Live.

Aug. 2020 - Dic. 2020 **Diploma in Data Science and Machine Learning**, Universidad Nacional de Colombia.

Feb. 2012 - Jul. 2017 System Engineer, Universidad del Valle.

Awards

• Laureate Degree Thesis

References

Andrés Fernando Valencia, Electronic Engineer, UX/UI Engineer, Markaf Co-

lombia S.A.S.

Contact: +57 318 271 0945

Mónica María Monsalve, System Engineer, Technology Director, El País

Newspaper.

Contact: +57 311 321 8456

MOOCs Courses

- Apache Airflow
- ReactJS Introduction
- \circ RESTFul API using Python and Django Rest Framework

